Benjamin Cole

35 Meade Road, Ambler, PA 19002

Phone: 215-206-5486 Website: https://bearfaic.github.io/

benjamin.cole95@gmail.com

Programmer experienced in both writing code, and working with a team. Automated weekly tasks for the Vertex Object Oriented Design team, saving hours of work per month, as well as analyzed SQL tables to build marketing tools directly under members of the Vertex executive team.

Experience

American University

October 2018 - May 2018

Teachers Assistant/Tutor

Worked with students of all grades in the CSC-280 Intro to Computer Science class to help them understand the material, teach techniques not covered in class, and provide homework help. Students who went to TA hours were better equipped for tests and classwork, and noticed an increase in homework grades.

Vertex Inc.

May 2016 - August 2016

Berwyn PA

Vertex Intern - Object Oriented Java Development Team

Worked with the commercial software development team, using Java, Python and SQL to complete the following projects:

- Executed the full product build process in order to participate in reviewing Java code and learning the underlying database structures that support the application.
- Wrote SQL queries used to analyze a production system with the purpose of creating a automatic database sizing recommendations spreadsheet based on different data profiles, used by the Database Development and Content Management teams.
- Wrote Python scripts to automate recurring processing, such as adding users to new builds of the Vertex Enterprise product for use by the Business Intelligence Development team, saving several hours of recurring set up time every month.

Target, Plymouth Meeting PA

May 2015 - August 2015

Cashier and Team Member

- Interacted with the general public, maintaining professional composure under pressure.
- Received consistently positive customer and supervisory reviews, parted on good terms.

Bitcamp Hackathon, College Park, MD

April 2016

Built a working multimedia app utilizing APIs and a GUI as leader of a small team.
 Program took music files found on a windows computer or phone, and used Bing API to determine "the internet's opinion" of an individual's musical tastes.

Drexel University Computing Academy, Philadelphia PA June 2013 - July 2013

Worked with a team to write and create a playable, original video game, featuring fully animated 3d models, and a self building unique maze system, created anew upon game restart.

Education:

- American University Computer Science, Anticipated BS May 2018
- Wissahickon High School Diploma May 2014

Tools:

Java, Python, C#, Perl, C++, Matlab, SQL, Html5, Javascript, CSS, PHP, Linux (CentOS, Mint)